simplyhired.co.uk 2016-06-12

# Privacy | Simply Hired

**Effective Date: May 27, 2016**

This Privacy Policy was last updated: May 27, 2016

Simply Hired, Inc. ("Simply Hired") has drafted its Privacy Policy to ensure that you can clearly understand our data and security practices and policies as you use Simply Hired's websites and software applications (the "Sites"). This Privacy Policy describes the types of Personal Information we collect, how we use the information, with whom we share it, and the choices you can make about our collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information. The phrase "Personal Information" refers to information that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card number or other billing information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of your Personal Information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices. 

This Privacy Policy incorporates by reference the [Terms Of Use](http://www.simplyhired.co.uk/about/terms-of-service) for the Sites, which apply to this Privacy Policy. When you visit the Sites or provide us with information, you consent to our use and disclosure of the information we collect or receive, as described in this Privacy Policy, unless separate terms are offered by you in writing and accepted in writing by Simply Hired. 

Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, as we may update it from time to time without prior notice to reflect changes in our data practices. We will post a prominent notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the bottom of the notice when it was most recently updated. If we make material changes to the policy that will affect previously collected Personal Information, you will be notified and asked to consent to the updated Privacy Policy when you visit our Sites. 

## Overview

  * Information We Collect

In addition to collecting information about you when you use our Sites, we may also obtain information about you from our business partners, other third parties and publicly available information.

Additional Details

  * How We Use the Information We Collect

The information we collect is principally used to (i) register, manage and maintain your account on the Sites; (ii) provide products or services you request; and (iii) inform you of relevant job postings that may be of interest to you.

Additional Details

  * Information We Share

When you apply for a job through the Sites or upload your resume to the Sites, employers will have access to information about you and your potential interest in employment opportunities.

We also may share Personal Information with our service providers who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you.

We may combine certain non-personally identifiable Aggregate Data about our users and use such anonymous Aggregate Data to prepare reports for our clients and business partners (typically employers or educators).

Additional Details

  * Resume Privacy Options

When you upload your resume to the Sites, you will have the option to choose between the following 2 levels of privacy.

**Option 1** makes your resume discoverable in our resume database. By selecting this option, your resume and contact details (to the extent you provide them or include them in your resume) can be discovered and viewed by any registered employer user who posts jobs on the Sites. This setting enables you to be found by employers who are seeking candidates matching your background and experience for their open positions. We also may share Personal Information with our service providers who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. 

**Option 2** makes your resume private and hidden from our employer users, though you will still be able to use it to apply for jobs on the Sites. Please note that this setting only applies to whether or not your resume is visible to employers. Simply Hired will still collect, use or disclose anonymous aggregate information about you and your visits in the manner described below. You may choose to remove your resume from our resume database at any time. However, you may still be contacted by employers or recruiters who retain a copy of your resume in their own files or databases. 

  * Updating Your Account Information

You may access, update and amend Personal Information included in your online account at any time by logging into your account and making the necessary changes.

Additional Details

  * How We Protect Personal Information

Simply Hired maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to assist us in protecting the Personal Information we collect against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

Additional Details

  * "Children's Privacy" 

We do not knowingly collect or solicit information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not use the Sites. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. 

Additional Details

  * Additional Disclosures
    * Cookies, Tracking Choices and Third Party Advertisers
    * Links to Other Websites
    * International Data Transfers

  * How to Contact Us

You can direct questions regarding this Privacy Policy to Simply Hired by emailing us at: [privacy@simplyhired.com](mailto:privacy@simplyhired.com). Please include your name and email address in email requests. 

## Information We Collect

In addition to collecting information about you when you use our Sites, we may also obtain information about you from our business partners, other third parties and publicly available information.

The types of information we may obtain include:

  * Your Personal Information, if you choose to provide it or if we obtain it in the manner described above. Please note that you are not required to provide us with any Personal Information in order to perform job searches or to read the content portions of the Sites. 
  * Username and password for the account you may establish on our Sites.
  * Payment details (including payment card number, security code, expiration date, cardholder name and billing address) if you purchase products or services on our Sites.
  * Your demographic information (such as ZIP or postal code, occupation, education, experience, age, gender and race or ethnicity). We collect this information either through the registration process, from your resume or in the manner described above. 
  * Job search behavior and preferences and a record of the searches that you make on our Sites. We do this in order to present you with recommendations based on your interests as expressed previously through your activities on our Sites. 
  * Other details that you may submit to us or that may be included in the information provided to us by third parties.

We may collect information stored in your social media profile that you authorize us to access when you use your social media profile to invoke features on the Sites, such as the ability to pre-populate our registration form or a job application. Simply Hired provides software applications ("Apps") available to the public. If you decide to download one of our Apps and create an account via social media, we will collect your profile information, including your social network site user ID, work email address, name, city, state, social network site profile image URL, and employment history, including job titles and company names. 

In addition, when you visit our Sites or use our Apps, we may collect certain information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below.The information we may collect by automated means includes: 

  * Information about the devices you use to access the Internet (such as the IP address and the device, browser and operating system type).
  * Pages and URLs that refer you to our Sites, as well as pages and URLs to which you navigate once you leave our Sites.
  * Dates and times of your visits to our Sites.
  * Information about your actions on our Sites (such as page views, site navigation patterns and job view or application activity).
  * A general geographic location (such as country and city) from which you access our Sites.
  * Search terms that you use to reach our Sites.

(Return to Top)

## How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use the information we obtain about you to:

  * Register, manage and maintain your account on the Sites.
  * Provide products or services you request.
  * Process, validate and deliver your purchases (including processing payment card transactions and contacting you about your orders via email or telephone).
  * Maintain a record of the jobs you view or apply to on our Sites.
  * Inform you of relevant job postings that may be of interest to you.
  * Provide administrative notices or communications applicable to your use of the Sites.
  * Respond to your questions and comments and provide customer support.
  * Contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests (such as relevant services, educational or other career development opportunities); enable you to communicate with us through our blogs, social networks and other interactive media; and solicit your feedback and input. These communications will contain links for preference management and, where appropriate, unsubscribe links, should you decide you do not want to receive further communications. 
  * Manage your participation in our events and other promotions, where you have signed up for such events and promotions.
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business and the products and services we offer.
  * Analyze and enhance our marketing communications and strategies (including identification of when emails we have sent to you have been received and read).
  * Analyze trends and statistics regarding visitors' use of our Sites, mobile applications and social media assets, and the jobs viewed or applied to on our Sites.
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized transactions, claims and other liabilities, and manage risk exposure, including by identifying potential hackers and other unauthorized users.
  * Enforce our Sites' [Terms Of Use](http://www.simplyhired.co.uk/about/terms-of-service) . 
  * Comply with applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies.

We also use non-personally identifiable information and certain technical information about your computer and your access of the Sites (including your IP address) in order to operate, maintain and manage the Sites. We collect this information by automated means, such as cookies and web beacons, as described in more detail below. 

If we seek to use the information we obtain about you in other ways, we will provide specific notice and request your consent at the time of collection.

(Return to Top)

## Information We Share

When you apply for a job through the Sites or upload your resume to the Sites, employers will have access to information about you and your potential interest in employment opportunities. Those employers may use your information to contact you directly. Additionally, when you apply for a job through the Sites, the information supplied by you becomes part of the Simply Hired database but also may become part of the employer's database. Similarly, if an employer downloads your resume, your resume may become a part of the employer's database. In these instances, the use of such information by the employer will be subject to the privacy policy of that company, and we are not responsible for that company's use of your information. 

The Sites may track the total number of visitors to our Sites, the number of visitors to each page of our Sites, IP addresses, External Web Sites linked to, search terms and the domain names of our users' Internet Service Providers, operating system and browser type, and we may analyze these data for trends and statistics in the aggregate, but such information will be maintained, used and disclosed in aggregate form only and it will not contain personally identifiable information. We also may collect aggregate information such as demographics including age, occupation, gender, salary information and labor statistics. Such aggregate information may be collected from data that you have provided to us via usage of the Sites and/or public records, and is not unique to you nor is it linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We may use such aggregate information to analyze trends, administer the Sites, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We may share this aggregate information with third parties, including for various reasons related to our business to assist them in targeting advertisements to appropriate audiences. 

Other than instances in which users opt to publicly post their Personal Information to our resume database, provide it via a job application, include it in a job posting or otherwise provide permission to share it, we do not sell our users' Personal Information to anyone for any reason. When posting jobs and resumes, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display. 

We share Personal Information with our service providers who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. These service providers may only use or disclose the information as necessary to perform services on our behalf or as otherwise required by law. 

Simply Hired also may disclose specific user information when we determine, in good faith, that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, to cooperate with or seek assistance from law enforcement, to prevent a crime or protect national security, or to protect the interests or safety of Simply Hired or other users of the Sites.

Personal Information we have collected may be passed on to a third party in the event of a bankruptcy or another corporate reorganization of Simply Hired. In addition, if we are acquired by or merged with another company, or in the event of any sale of assets or other transfer of ownership by Simply Hired to a third party, the Personal Information we have collected may be transferred to such third party as well as such third party’s affiliates and subsidiaries.

(Return to Top)

## About Cookies, Tracking Choices, and Third Party Advertisers

By using our Sites, you consent to Simply Hired's policies and practices concerning Cookies, Tracking Choices, and Third Party Advertisers, as follows:

A "cookie" is a text file that websites send to a visitor‘s computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor's browser or to store information or settings in the browser. A "Web beacon" can also be called a Web bug, a pixel tag or a clear GIF. Used in combination with cookies, a Web beacon is an often-transparent graphic image, usually no larger than 1 pixel x 1 pixel, that is placed on a website or in an email and used to monitor the behavior of the user visiting the website or receiving the email. 

Other than instances in which users opt to publicly post their Personal Information to our resume database, provide it via a job application, include it in a job posting or otherwise provide permission to share it, we do not sell our users' Personal Information to anyone for any reason. When posting jobs and resumes, our users decide for themselves how much contact information they wish to display. 

Simply Hired uses cookies, and other similar technologies, for the convenience of our users. Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly. Simply Hired also uses cookies placed on your computer to store non-personally identifying information about you, such as past jobs viewed and job searches conducted on your computer. We do this in order to present you with job recommendations based on your interests, as expressed previously through your searches. 

Simply Hired uses cookies to ensure the proper functioning and efficiency of our Sites. Most web browsers enable you to erase cookies from your computer's hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please be aware, however, that some Simply Hired features or services may not function properly without cookies. 

Simply Hired permits third-party cookies on its Sites. For example, third-party tools located on the Sites, including those that allow for social media sharing, may use cookies to remember user preference settings. Simply Hired also uses web analytics services provided by third parties, which use cookies to collect non-personal information about users' visits to the Sites (including IP addresses) and the resources they access on the Sites. These third-party web analytics services provide us with reports based on this non-personal information in order to help us understand how visitors engage with our Sites. In addition, these third-party web analytics services may share aggregate data with third-party advertising companies to enable interest-based and retargeting advertising services. 

Simply Hired uses third-party advertising companies that may place or access cookies on your computer's hard drive to distinguish your web browser uniquely and keep track of information related to serving ads on your web browser, such as the types of ads shown and the web pages on which the ads appeared. These companies may use information about your visits to our Sites and to other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you on our Sites or on other, third-party sites. We may also allow third-party advertisers to tailor their advertisements on our Sites using demographic and preference information we provide to them in aggregate form. This information does not identify you individually. 

The third-party advertising companies used by Simply Hired operate under their own privacy policies and we encourage you to be aware of the privacy policies of such companies. Simply Hired does not have control over or access to any information contained in the cookies that are set on your computer by third-party advertisers. 

Our Sites do not respond to web browser "do not track" signals. However, to help prevent and limit the automatic collection of information by any participating third-party advertisers, including the collection of personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services, you may opt-out of such collection by clicking the AdChoices icon located in the ad, by accessing the ["about ads" opt-out site](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or by accessing the [NAI opt-out site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please note that this opt-out is cookie-based. If you buy a new computer, change web browsers or delete this cookie, you will need to perform each opt-out task again. 

In addition, some employers using our Sites may place cookies on your computer through their job postings and may use such cookies to distinguish your web browser uniquely. Often, employers use such information to track the effectiveness of their job postings by measuring how many users who view their postings later become job applicants. 

Finally, Simply Hired has enabled the Remarketing Lists feature of Google Analytics Advertising Features. Together, Simply Hired and Google use both first-party and third-party cookies to serve customized ads to you based on your past visits to our Sites. This means that Simply Hired promotional material might appear on a variety of other websites you visit across the web. 

You may opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising Features by visiting the [Google Ads Preferences Manager](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). To prevent your web usage data from being used by Google Analytics, you may also download and install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

(Return to Top)

## Update Your Account Information

You may access, update and amend Personal Information included in your online account at any time by logging into your account and making the necessary changes. You may access, review and update (including changing or deleting parts of your account information) the information in your account at any time. However, if you wish to delete the entirety of the information you have provided to us, you must first access and close your account by going [here](http://www.simplyhired.co.uk/account/). Upon successful closure of your account, you may create a new account with your updated Personal Information. 

(Return to Top)

## International Data Transfers

When we obtain Personal Information about you, we may process and store the information outside of the country in which you are located, including in the United States. The countries in which we process the information may not have data protection laws that offer equivalent protection for your information as the country in which you are located. Further, users who access your information, such as potential employers, also may be located in a different country than you and different laws may apply to their use of your information. By accessing and registering with the Sites you consent to the use, disclosure and transfer of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and subject to the laws of the United States. 

(Return to Top)

## How We Protect Personal Information

Simply Hired maintains administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to assist us in protecting the Personal Information we collect against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.

We have taken appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your information from misuse, unauthorized or unlawful access or disclosure, loss, alteration, damage or destruction. These measures include:

  * Physical safeguards that include storing data in areas with controlled access.
  * Technology safeguards that include using Sophos anti-virus and endpoint protection software encryption, and monitoring of our systems and data centers to ensure that they comply with our security policies.
  * Organizational safeguards that include training and awareness programs on security and privacy, to make sure our employees and contractors understand the importance and means by which they must protect your information. Our organizational privacy policies and standards also guide our handling of your information. 

Please note that the information we collect from you may be stored on servers in the United States and anywhere Simply Hired or our vendors operate. By accessing and registering with the Sites you consent to the use, disclosure and transfer of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and subject to the laws of the United States. 

(Return to Top)

## Links to Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites that are owned or operated by other companies. If you choose to visit any linked websites, we encourage you to review their privacy statements carefully, as they may differ from ours. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites that are owned by companies outside the Simply Hired group of companies. 

Our websites may also link to co-branded websites that are maintained by Simply Hired and one or more of our business partners, who are collecting your Personal Information pursuant to their own privacy practices. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on any co-branded site to which you link for information on the privacy practices of that site. 

Please note that no electronic transmission of information can be entirely secure. We cannot guarantee that the security measures we have in place to safeguard Personal Information will never be defeated or fail, or that those measures will always be sufficient or effective. Therefore, although we are committed to protecting your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your Personal Information will always remain private. As a user of the Sites, you understand and agree that you assume all responsibility and risk for your use of the Sites and the internet generally, the documents you post or access and for your conduct on and off the Sites. 

To further protect yourself, you should safeguard your Simply Hired account username and password and not share that information with anyone. You should also sign off your account and close your browser window when you have finished your visit to our Sites. Please note that we will never ask for your Simply Hired account username or password via email. Should you forget your password, we will send you a password reset email that will direct you to a password reset webpage on our Sites. 

(Return to Top)

## Children's Privacy

We do not knowingly collect or solicit information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not use the Sites. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. 

Minors of working age who use the site and wish to have their publicly available content removed may do so by sending a request via email to [privacy@simplyhired.com](mailto:privacy@simplyhired.com). 

(Return to Top)

## How to Contact Us

You can direct questions regarding this Privacy Policy to Simply Hired by emailing us at [privacy@simplyhired.com](mailto:privacy@simplyhired.com) Please include your name and email address in email requests 

(Return to Top)
